

Profile

Recent chemical engineering graduate with hands on experience in **Backend Development with Django, Node.js and MongoDB, Artificial Intelligence, AI Product Management,** building **Machine Learning Models** for classification and prediction, analysing data and presenting findings to senior officials with confidence. Possess sound communication, analytical, leadership, and problem-solving abilities, quick understanding and use of new technologies and tools.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering, Federal University of Technology, Owerri, Imo January 2016 - November 2021

Machine Learning Engineer Nanodegree, Udacity

September 2020 — November 2020

Al Product Manager Nanodegree, Udacity

March 2021 — November 2021

Experience

Machine Learning Engineer at Heroi, Tunis

January 2021 — Present

Backend Developer Intern at Genesys Tech Hub

September 2021 — Present

Data Analysis and Visualization Intern at Taken Mind

November 2019 — February 2020

Laboratory Assistant Intern at Copaci Cosmetics

September 2019 — December 2019

Projects

Dog Breed Classifier Using CNNs

October 2020 — November 2020

- Built a CNN model using pytorch from scratch, which achieved a 45% accuracy on the test set after 200 training epochs.
- Utilized transfer learning to increase accuracy to 86% on the test set after 30 training epochs.
- Wrote an algorithm that overlays dog filters on images.
- Added a functionality to classify dog mutts with an accuracy of 60%
- Deployed the models in a pipeline to a web app using flask

Plagiarism Detector

September 2020 — September 2020

- Built a machine learning model that examines a text file and perform binary classification, labelling that file as either plagiarized or not, depending on how similar the text file is to a provided source text.
- Deployed the plagiarism model using AWS SageMaker.

Find More Projects in my Portfolio and Github profile.

Details

Lagos, Nigeria, +2349035485284 realchidinweke@gmail.com

Date of birth

02-06-1997

Nationality

Nigerian

Links

Github LinkedIn Portfolio

Skills

Communication Skills

Microsoft Office

Java

JavaScript

Node.js

MongoDB

Git

Python

Languages

English

French

Hobbies

Music directing, Singing, Puzzles, DIY

➤ Leadership

Facilitator and Team Lead: Design Genesys Learnable '21 Design Sprint Week.

- · Conducted and scheduled virtual team meetings.
- Allotted tasks and processes, and acted as a supervisor to keep team on track.
- Effectively kept team in constant communication by sending mails and pings to team members.
- Employed a democratic leadership style to encourage every team member to become actively involved in the sprint.
- Led the team to successfully develop a working solution from the exercise.

Music Director at St. Thomas Acquinas Chaplaincy Choir, Owerri January 2020 — July 2021

 Led and supervised a fourty-man committee to organize the best and biggest yet (according to reviews) student musical concert in South-East Nigeria in just two months, with refreshments for over 1000 audience and a revenue of up to two million NGN for the choir.

Student Leader at Udacity Bertelsmann Scholarship Challenge

December 2020 — February 2021

• Helped students to pass the first phase of scholarship by engaging them in daily motivational quotes and answering their technical questions.

Courses

Python for Data Science, Udemy July 2019

Data Analysis and Visualization, Udemy

November 2019 — February 2020